<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frederick Boehm&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Frederick Boehm&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Frederick Boehm</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:16:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/static/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/static/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Short courses and workshops  Data Carpentry Social Sciences  January 25-26, 2019, Arlington, Virginia, USA   Data Carpentry Genomics  September 15-16, 2018, Rolla, Missouri, USA   Preparing to teach statistics (instructor)  Spring 2018  Topic models for computational text analysis  Summer 2016, Fall 2013    Formal courses  Educating a diverse nation (co-facilitator)  Spring 2017 (in-person) &amp;amp; Fall 2017 (online)  Introductory statistics (instructor of record)  Fall 2016, Spring 2016, Fall 2015, Summer 2015, Spring 2015, Fall 2014, Spring 2014    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>/static/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/static/software/</guid>
      <description>  qtl2pleio: Testing pleiotropy vs. separate QTL in multiparental populations  
 gemma2: Multivariate random effects for genetics studies 
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/static/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/static/publications/</guid>
      <description>Peer-reviewed journal articles Tauchman, E. C, F. J. Boehm and J. G. DeLuca (2015). “Stable kinetochore-microtubule attachment is sufficient to silence the spindle assembly checkpoint in human cells”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>/static/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 09:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/static/presentations/</guid>
      <description>International Mammalian Genome Conference, November 11-14, 2018, Rio Mar, Puerto Rico    Winner of best poster award  Joint Statistical Meetings, August 1, 2018, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World-wide Web and Social Media</title>
      <link>/blog/internet-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/internet-social-media/</guid>
      <description>I’ve followed a series of blog posts from Cal Newport at http://calnewport.com/blog/ (with posts like this) in which Newport criticizes social media platforms for, among other things, limiting the scope of internet browsing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package site incorporation into my personal website</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11-24-r-package-site-with-pkgdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 10:01:53 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11-24-r-package-site-with-pkgdown/</guid>
      <description>Overview I’ve been developing the R package qtl2pleio. It’s now at a stage where others can use it. I recently found the R package pkgdown, which allows developers to build, in an automated fashion, websites for their packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reticulate R package &amp; Travis</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-04-01-reticulate-r-package-travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-04-01-reticulate-r-package-travis/</guid>
      <description>I like to use Travis CI with my R packages. I recently wrote a R package, limmbo2, that is a wrapper for the python module limmbo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>limmbo2 R package now on Github</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-03-30-limmbo2-r-package-now-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-03-30-limmbo2-r-package-now-on-github/</guid>
      <description>I have posted to Github the R package limmbo2. limmbo2 is a R wrapper to the freely available python module limmbo. I mention my interest in limmbo in an earlier blog post, so I won’t repeat it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with the reticulate R package</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-03-19-getting-started-with-the-reticulate-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-03-19-getting-started-with-the-reticulate-r-package/</guid>
      <description>Motivation My colleague Rene Welch brought to my attention a recent pre-print, “LiMMBo: a simple, scalable approach for linear mixed models in high-dimensional genetic association studies” by Hannah Meyer, Francesco Casale, Oliver Stegle, and Ewan Birney.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joan Didion’s &#34;On self-respect&#34;</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-09-10-joan-didion-s-on-self-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-09-10-joan-didion-s-on-self-respect/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I read for the first time Joan Didion’s essay “On self-respect” in her 1968 collection of essays “Slouching towards Bethlehem”. “On self-respect” originally appeared in Vogue in 1961.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pkgdown R package for generating package websites on Github</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-04-12-pkgdown-for-generating-package-websites-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-04-12-pkgdown-for-generating-package-websites-on-github/</guid>
      <description>I recently learned about the R package, pkgdown, an R package that provides functions that make it easy to build a website from an R package on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Writing by Donald Knuth, Tracy Larrabee, and Paul Roberts</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-08-16-mathematical-writing-by-donald-knuth-tracy-larrabee-and-paul-roberts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-08-16-mathematical-writing-by-donald-knuth-tracy-larrabee-and-paul-roberts/</guid>
      <description>I recently applied for a peer review training program that the Genetics Society of America organizes. An advisor kindly agreed to write a recommendation for my application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Roberts&#39;s Commencement Address</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-03-john-roberts-s-commencement-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-03-john-roberts-s-commencement-address/</guid>
      <description>This afternoon, while listening to “All Things Considered” on Wisconsin Public Radio, I heard an excerpt from John Roberts’s recent commencement address. Here is the story from “All Things Considered”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with blogdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-07-getting-started-with-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-07-getting-started-with-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>While browsing the internet, I stumbled upon Rstudio’s new package blogdown. I read posts from Karl Broman and found the the book that the package author - Yihui Xie - freely shares.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>